returnpath.net 2002-12-04

# Return Path - Your Email Change of Address Solution - Your E-mail Change of Address Solution - Privacy Policy

**Return Path's Privacy Promise**  
We take privacy very seriously, and we've taken many steps to help safeguard your online information. We promise you that:  [](http://www.bbbonline.org/cks.asp?id=200121217282311790)

  * We will safeguard, according to strict standards of security, any information you share with us. 
  * We will not share information you provide us without your permission. 
  * We will not send unsolicited e-mails. 
  * You can unsubscribe from our service at any time. 

Return Path is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program and the BBBOnline Privacy and Dispute Resolution Program. This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for [www.returnpath.net](http://www.returnpath.net/). Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to disclose our information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe and BBBOnline.

TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices.

A wholly owned subsidiary of the Council of Better Business Bureaus, BBBOnLine's mission is to promote trust and confidence on the Internet through the BBBOnLine Reliability and BBBOnLine Privacy programs.

Please read our Privacy Policy below for more information.

**Return Path Privacy Policy**  

**_Introduction_**

Return Path offers an e-mail change of address service that helps people stay in touch with their family, friends, business contacts, web sites and e-mail subscriptions. We know that you're concerned with privacy on the Internet, and we've taken many steps to help safeguard your online information and protect your privacy.

Return Path is committed to protecting your privacy and to ensuring that you are in control of the information that we maintain about you. The Return Path privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") explains what we will and will not do with your personal information. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "personal information" means individually identifiable information about a user collected online, including a user's first and last name, home or other physical address, e-mail address or telephone number.

Returnpath.net is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/users/watchdog.html>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns.

Return Path also participates in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine Privacy and Dispute Resolution Programs; and has been certified by BBBOnLine Privacy as meeting all the BBBOnLine Privacy requirements. For more information about either of these programs, please refer to the links below:

  * <http://www.truste.org/>
  * <http://www.bbbonline.org/>

Return Path's policies and procedures are based on the eight internationally recognized privacy principles issued in 1980 by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development in its [Guidelines for Fair Information Practices](http://www1.oecd.org/dsti/sti/it/secur/prod/PRIV-EN.HTM). The principles pertaining to fair information practices in use at Return Path are as follows:

  * Use Limitation
  * Individual Participation
  * Security Safeguards
  * Openness
  * Collection Limitation
  * Purpose Specification
  * Data Quality
  * Accountability

Additional important information is located in the following sections:

  * Policy Regarding Children's Use of Our Site
  * Business Transfers or Bankruptcy
  * Notification of Changes

**_Use Limitation_ **

Return Path treats your personal information as confidential and does not disclose it or use it except as permitted by you, as described in this privacy policy, or as required by law, subpoena, court order, legal process or a warrant.

If we are served with a civil subpoena seeking personal information about a Return Path user, we will use reasonable efforts to notify the specified user of the request prior to disclosure of such personal information, so as to allow the user the opportunity to oppose the subpoena.

Return Path will not provide your e-mail address, name, or other personal identifiers to merchants or marketers without your prior permission. Return Path will follow the instructions you indicate through the Return Path software interface or e-mails we send to you.

Return Path may engage third parties to perform analysis or data processing of our databases that involves access to your personal information, in order to better provide you with the services for which you joined. If Return Path does so, it will ensure that such parties are contractually required to keep the information confidential and not to use it in any way other than as is necessary to perform their work for Return Path.

Return Path may disclose summary information obtained by combining data from many individuals (never fewer than 25, and typically thousands or more), but with all personal identifiers removed.

back to top

**_Individual Participation_**

As a Return Path member, you have access to, and appropriate control over, the data that Return Path maintains about you.

Return Path gives you easy access to the information maintained about you in the Return Path database in a format that is easy to understand. Our current policy is to collect your old and new e-mail address from you when you register your e-mail address change at the Return Path web site or at a Return Path network partner web site. Return Path limits user access to verification of your old and new e-mail addresses, and settings for handling E-mail Change of Address notifications to personal and commercial contacts. Should this access policy change, Return Path will post the changed policy on this web site.

Return Path provides you with options that enable you to determine how you want to handle notifications to personal and commercial contacts regarding your changed e-mail address. These options let you either determine who may receive your new e-mail address, or grant Return Path permission to share your new e-mail address with anyone who knows your old e-mail address and is a Return Path-approved network partner or an individual using the service to get back in touch with you. Regardless of the option you choose, you decide how your information is shared.

To revise or edit your personally identifiable information, simply go to the Address Manager tab on the Return Path web site. Use your new e-mail address as your log-in ID. Return Path, upon recognizing your valid Log-in ID will send an e-mail to your new e-mail address, containing the link for access to Address Manager. However, a request to revise or edit your personally identifiable information may not be accommodated if it would result in incorrect information. Requests for deletion of certain key information, such as e-mail address, may require closing the account.

Most requests for access to personal data are processed within seconds of being made through the Return Path software Web interface. Some requests may take up to a few days to process, and the results may be delivered by e-mail.

Any other questions should be addressed to [support@returnpath.net](mailto:support@returnpath.net).

Information about a member may be withheld or exempted from deletion if this is required by law or is part of a fraud investigation.

**Unsubscribe Procedures:**

If you decide that you do not wish to participate in our service you can unsubscribe by clicking on the link provided in any e-mail message Return Path sends you and following the directions provided. Additionally, you can remove your account information directly from the Return Path web site by going to the Address Manager, after logging in, and clicking the link marked "Remove Old addresses".

back to top

**_Security Safeguards_**

We ensure information quality by employing advanced technology to protect our users' data. We also have well-defined employee and network partner practices that protect the integrity of and access to our users' information.

At Return Path we employ security techniques and well-defined employee practices to ensure that data is protected from unauthorized access and use. We hold our employees and network partners accountable for maintaining the privacy and integrity of our users' information. Return Path provides ongoing training programs that are designed to keep our employees and network partners informed of our Privacy Policies.

Return Path may engage employees, contractors, and other companies to perform work that involves access to personal information. If Return Path does so, it will ensure that such parties are contractually required to keep the information confidential and not to use it in any way other than as is necessary to perform their work for Return Path.

Return Path works to reduce the likelihood of accidental disclosures and unintended access and modification of account information, but it is impossible to eliminate this possibility completely.

To access the information Return Path holds about you, use your new e-mail address as your log-in ID. Return Path, upon recognizing your valid Log-in ID will send an e-mail to your new e-mail address, containing the link for access to Address Manager. If you allow others to have access to your new e-mail address box, that is--allow them to access and read your e-mail--they may be able to gain access to your Return Path account. To maintain the highest level of security for your Return Path account, you should not provide others with access to your e-mail address box.

We conduct internal and external audits to determine the effectiveness of our compliance with our Privacy Policy. Our Return Path-approved network partners are contractually and legally obligated to follow agreed-upon privacy practices. If a Return Path user feels that they have experienced a violation of these privacy policies, they should contact us at:

Return Path, Inc.  
Attention: Privacy  
56 West 22nd Street, 10th Floor  
New York, New York, 10010

Fax: 212-905-5501  
E-mail: [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net)

back to top

**_Openness_**

Return Path has a general policy of openness about developments, practices and policies with respect to personal data. Return Path states in detail what personal data it collects and why it collects it.

Return Path's Web server may log key information about any visitor to the Return Path web site (both users and non-users), including the following elements:

  * The URL of the page requested; 
  * The time and date of the request; 
  * The "User Agent" (the make and model of the web browser being used, and the version and type of your operating system); 
  * The "Referrer" (the URL where you clicked on a link to Return Path's site); 
  * The IP address where a copy of the page you requested is to be sent for display by your browser. 

Return Path "anonymizes" its server logs periodically. Return Path summarizes each element it tracks, such as User Agent and Referrer, the number of visits from higher-level domains, and so on. The individual records are destroyed, thus cutting the link between a particular IP address and the other server elements listed above. Although an IP address does not usually identify the visitor personally, it does suggest an individual association in some cases, which is one reason why we "anonymize" the logs.

We use this information in aggregate to get a better picture of where our visitors come from and how to plan for our future needs.

The web server logs may be used in the course of a fraud investigation.

The User Agent also is used during your visit to indicate to you whether Return Path's software will run on your computer's configuration. The URL may contain tracking codes used only for the purpose of auditing advertising.

**Our Use of Cookies:**

At the present time, Return Path will be using cookies to manage the session between your browser and our web site. Cookies will also be used to allow you to have a unique ID for access to our services. We will not collect any personally identifiable information via the use of cookies. Any information we collect using cookies will be used only for the purposes of web site administration and will not be shared with anyone. Should our policy change regarding the use of cookies, Return Path will post those changes to our privacy policy.

A "cookie" is a small piece of information sent by a web server to store on a web browser so it can later be read back from that browser. This is useful for having the browser remember some specific information. An example is when a browser stores your passwords and user IDs. They are also used to store preferences of start pages. Both Microsoft and Netscape use cookies to create personal start pages.

Cookies are used to make informed guesses about you. They can be used to access information about your web activities including things like sites you've visited, passwords and purchases you've made. Companies can only make guesses about who you are because cookies do not necessarily contain personal information about you. Cookies alone are not invasive of your privacy and actually provide benefits to you. Much of what you find on the web today is free because advertising, similar to television and radio, supports it. Advertising, in part, is driven by the information contained in cookies. Cookies provide an effective way for the web sites you visit to personalize your experience when you visit them. In fact, many sites actually require that a cookie be "dropped" on your computer in order for these sites to recognize you and work properly when you visit them.

**Our Use of Clear GIF's:**

Return Path uses a common technology called a clear gif or action tags. A clear gif (graphic interface format) is a small graphic image that is a 1x1 pixel placed on our web site, in banner ads, and/or in e-mail communications. A clear gif provides us with important information about how members use our web site and respond to our e-mail communications, such as whether someone is using an e-mail reader that understands HTML e-mail messages. This information helps us understand the effectiveness of our web-based communications and improve it's effectiveness.

back to top

**_Collection Limitation_**

Return Path collects personal data about you only in ways that are fair and lawful. Return Path collects only the personal data it has said it collects, and only in the ways it has said it collects it.

back to top

**_Purpose Specification_**

Return Path always specifies the purposes for which it uses personal data, before collecting it. Return Path will not use it for other purposes without first obtaining the member's consent.

**Who Collects Your Information:**

Return Path collects e-mail address change information at our web site, [www.returnpath.net](http://www.returnpath.net/), and at network partner web sites with a pop-up window hosted by Return Path. Return Path's network partners may also collect information from you when you update your e-mail address at their web sites, and may then send the information to us if you have opted-in to the Return Path e-mail change of address service.

**Information We Collect:**

When you register your e-mail address change at a Return Path web site or at a Return Path network partner web site, we ask you to provide your new and old e-mail addresses. When you press "submit," Return Path also records the time and date, as well as other administrative information that helps Return Path prevent people from misusing our system.

After you submit your e-mail address change, Return Path sends out a confirmation e-mail to both your new and old e-mail addresses. We do this to help prevent people from misusing our service. Our confirmation e-mails provide instructions on how to activate or cancel your registration.

In order to protect your online information and prevent misuse of our system, Return Path regularly records the time and date you opened the confirmation e-mail messages, what links you clicked, as well as other information that may help people you choose to receive your new e-mail address send messages to you in a format that you can receive. 

If you choose to send a greeting card to notify your friends, family and business contacts of your e-mail address change, Return Path will collect the e-mail addresses of the recipients. Return Path will also collect the first names and last names of the recipients of the greeting card, as well as a brief, personal message if you choose to include such information in the greeting card. Return Path will not use the recipients' names or e-mail addresses other than to deliver a greeting card (although the recipients may be presented with an opportunity to register for Return Path's free e-mail change of address service). 

If you are using our service to look for one of our users, we may ask you for your first and last name. We use your first and last name to identify you to the individual whose e-mail address you are asking us to locate for you. When you press "submit," Return Path also records the time and date, as well as other administrative information that helps Return Path prevent people from misusing our system. 

Return Path, when appropriate, sends strictly administrative e-mails regarding material changes in our privacy policy or relating to the Return Path service.

An e-mail address is used as your unique name when you login. You are responsible for maintaining control of the e-mail address, as personal information may be sent to it.

Return Path makes other uses of summary information obtained by combining data from many individuals (never fewer than 25, and typically thousands or more), where the name and other identifiers have been removed.

Any personal information collected during the course of customer service (your home phone number, for example) will only be used for the purpose of customer service. This information will not be linked to your account, nor will it be shared with anyone else.

In the future, Return Path may ask for additional information that will help us understand your use of e-mail, your interests and/or preferences, so that we may continue to enhance our services to best serve you. This information will not be shared with any third parties without your explicit permission, and the provision of this information is completely at your option.

If you become a Return Path user, you give us permission to use the information we have told you we use here, for the purposes stated here, according to the options you indicate via the Return Path software and web site.

**Information We Share:**

Once your e-mail address change has been registered, you decide who has access to your updated e-mail address. Individual visitors may come to our web site, [www.returnpath.net](http://www.returnpath.net/) and or a Return Path network partner's web site, to request your updated e-mail address. Return Path's network partners may also send us a list of e-mail addresses in an attempt to re-contact people whose e-mail addresses may have changed. Return Path provides your new e-mail address to requestors according to the permission option you selected when you registered, and/or how you respond to our notification e-mails. Once we have your permission, your new e-mail address will be provided to the network partner and the network partner's use of the new e-mail address will be covered by the network partner's privacy policies. Return Path contractually requires each of its network partners to include in its privacy policies a provision that provides you with the option to opt-out at any time from any e-mail communication subscriptions you have with the network partner. If you are unable to opt-out from one of our network partner's e-mail subscription lists, please contact us at [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net).

If you choose to send a greeting card to notify others of your e-mail change of address, Return Path will share your e-mail address with the recipients of the greeting card. Return Path will also share your first name and/or last name with the recipients of the greeting card. Return Path will not use the recipients' names or e-mail addresses other than to deliver a greeting card (although the recipients may be presented with an opportunity to register for Return Path's free e-mail change of address service).

Return Path shares additional technical information (for instance: whether the e-mail program you use can receive html e-mail) collected during the e-mail address change registration process with our network partners, in order for our partners to send you e-mail messages in a format (for instance: html or text) that you can receive. Return Path also shares aggregate information (for instance information gathered from log files like IP address, referring urls, and browser type) for research and development efforts. However, this information does not contain, nor is it tied, to personally identifiable information.

back to top

**_Data Quality_**

Return Path does not collect personal data from you that is not relevant to the purposes stated in its Privacy Policy. Return Path strives to keep all personal information accurate, complete, and up-to-date.

As described in our Terms and Conditions, Return Path may terminate your account for various reasons, such as if you ask us to or if you stop using it for a long time.

After a reasonable period of time (consistent with business requirements such as accounting), the personal information associated with terminated accounts will be destroyed or removed. From time to time, Return Path reduces the amount of data associated with active members by converting older data into summary statistics or destroying it.

back to top

**_Accountability_**

Return Path always has an employee designated as its data controller, who is accountable for ensuring that Return Path protects its members' privacy. Questions, concerns, issues or complaints may be sent to [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net).

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Return Path, Inc.  
56 West 22nd Street, 10th Floor  
New York, New York 10010  
Phone: 212-905-5500

Fax: 212-905-5501  
E-mail: [privacy@returnpath.net](mailto:privacy@returnpath.net)

back to top

**_Policy Regarding Children's Use of Our Site_**

Return Path complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. Return Path does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. Return Path requires users of this site to be at least 13 years of age.

back to top

**_Business Transfers or Bankruptcy_**

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy companies or assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the unlikely event that Return Path or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets. Return Path users will be notified of such business transfer or bankruptcy and be given the opportunity to opt-out of any such transfer.

back to top

**_Notification of Changes_**

The foregoing policy is effective as of July 2002. Return Path reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued use of Return Path's services following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. In the event that Return Path intends to change this policy, Return Path will post a message on the home page of its Web Site that states that the Privacy Policy has been changed, and will provide a link to the Privacy Policy. These postings will occur on Return Path's Web Site for at least 30 days prior to any material change.

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. However, if you have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated your account, then you will not be contacted. Nor will your personal information be used in this new manner.

back to top
